Saraba chikyuu yo, ai suru hito yo
Farewell Earth, and to the ones we love
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Yamato
Space Battleship
Soldiers of Love
Chikyuu wo sukuu shimei o obite tatakau otoko
Men fight on a mission to save Earth
Moeru roman
It's a burning passion
Dareka ga kore wo yaraneba naranu
Someone has to do this
Kitai no hito ga ore tachi naraba
We are the trusted ones
Ginga wo hanare Iscandar e harubaru nozomu
Leaving the Milky Way to go all the way to Iscandar
Uchuu Senkan Yamato
Space Battleship Yamato
Twenty-eight years ago
Our blue skin and blood are
truly unique in this vast universe.
Planet Garmillas
We're proud of our blue blood. Because of that we've maintained our pure bloodlines.
Desler's Personal Residence at the former Garmillas Presidential Office
Your Majesty Erich, is that true ?
The end is near for our home planet.
One hundred years at most.
Our blood is so pure that we can only live
on another planet for a short period of time.
That's just…
Uncle, we must find a new
planet to migrate to immediately.
But, Mathius, it's not so easy to find a planet
that can accept millions of people all at once.
Sulzer's Sun is very unique…
Do we even need to take the
second class citizens with us ?
What are you talking about ?!
Then, what do we do ?
Encourage propagation with second class citizens so we can live on another planet ?
That's absurd.
It's unthinkable to abandon our noble skin.
Then we must rely on Iscandar.
If we do that...
We'll have to obey that planet's…
Abelt…
Oh no…
What were the guards doing ?!
Those who have not taken the blood oath
shouldn't be involved in this matter.
Even the members of your
family must obey the code.
Uncle, please wait.
Abelt, pledge to maintain the secret right here…
…and spend your entire life searching for a settlement in order to save Garmillas from going extinct.
Brother Mathius…
You can do it.
Promise me, okay ?
Twenty-two years ago
Mathius…
Mother…
Mathius, please open your eyes.
Mathius, don't leave me alone.
Why won't you wake up ?
He was a hero of the unification war…
Gone just like that.
His wife just got pregnant.
The Desler family is cursed.
Some have natural talent, some don't.
If Mathius was the light…
…his brother Abelt would be the dark.
He's no match.
They'll stop calling me the brother of the great Mathius.
Mathius, where are you going ?
You can't go there…
Even so, you're unfair, Brother.
Why are you taking Mother's soul with you ?
Promise me, okay ?
You're shoving all the burden on me.
Eighteen years ago
Iscandar…
Starsia…
What did you do to me ?
Did you read my memory ?
Or perhaps it is I, who recalled my own memories
after coming into contact with an omnipotent entity.
Führer Desler…
Who cares.
What is your wish ?
If the Goddess of Telezart is what the legend says, you should know without me telling you.
You can't communicate with them that way.
Is that alright ?
It's more frustrating than expected to face someone who sees through everything.
Desler, don't !
No contact with Kodai yet ?
No.
What about Nagakura ?
I can't locate her.
Could that fleet be…?
Lieutenant Keyman, try cross-checking the
Garmillas fleet ID signals with your database.
I'll check.
Führer Desler, Teresa is not the kind of entity that can conveniently grant human wishes.
I'm aware of that.
Those who are summoned by Teresa are
supposed to fulfill their duty for the rightful future.
Mankind has had revelations of Teresa since before they learned to travel through the sea of stars.
Perhaps you can say,
"under the manipulation of," for the sake of the rightful future.
That includes me. I couldn't
lead my own life as I wanted.
Now, Teresa, display your grace
to the ones chosen by fate.
You're capable of doing things mankind can't.
All living things are bound by fate.
However, it's a result of their own choices…
…even if it appears to be wasteful or unfair.
I only show people the path.
How you make decisions in your life
changes that path, even the future.
Hanging between this universe and the afterlife, you can only watch how the world changes.
God is powerless.
All ships are decommissioned according to the records.
They've been wandering around space for 3 years after opposing the government's democratization.
They're a diehard Desler faction after all.
They don't seem to be aware of the allied channel between Garmillas and Earth.
You managed to hack in ?
Their system's completely unaware of me.
I can rewrite the friend-or-foe ID signal with ease.
It'll take 30 seconds for them to restore
their radar after noticing any abnormality.
Can you go ?
No problem in my Czvarke.
This is the only way to contact Kodai.
We'll draw the attention of the enemy fleet.
Desler, what did you expect of Teresa ?
Legend is just legend.
But Emperor Zorder has a different vision.
He's trying to neutralize Teresa's power.
Now that I have Teresa under my control,
I'm no longer his caged bird, but a negotiating rival.
Ancient Archelias heritage gave the Gatlantians
a military and scientific power they were unworthy of.
It's possible to realize my dream
by making use of their power.
I didn't expect anything from God in the first place.
I came here to obtain a bargaining
chip for my negotiations with Gatlantis.
You're trying to free the besieged Telezart,
which means, you're my enemy once again.
Do you know why the Emperor
is trying to suppress Teresa's power ?
If my assumption is correct, even if Gatlantis agrees to
negotiate with you, it'll only last for a short period of time.
The Emperor must want Teresa's power to…
Führer, I'm terribly sorry to deliver some bad news, but the Yamato has made a move.
Moving to intercept.
Commander, are you safe ?!
Nagakura, what the hell are you doing ?!
Just disobeying orders !
Full emergency descent !
Those guys are really tough !
Be careful !
Got it !
It's a lonely path. You must deceive
everyone who becomes involved with you.
You're not supposed to take a role like this.
You'll eventually betray the Yamato.
The Czvarke's reached the sea surface.
A large battleship is approaching from behind.
Emergency ascent !
Fighting you guys is so unpredictable.
Talan, do you read me ?
Get the ship back…
Why don't we call an end to this, Führer Desler ?
How can we end things that haven't
even been started yet, Yamato lad ?
I'm Kodai Susumu, Chief Tactical Officer of the Yamato.
I want you to withdraw your
troops and leave Telezart at once.
Kodai…
I see.
You're that kid.
You think you can convince someone
who has already "died" once ?
Kodai !
So reckless…
Those puppets won't shoot me,
but that's only while I'm alive.
So, why don't you pull the trigger ?
What's wrong, Kodai ?
If you don't have the courage…
Now's our chance, Nagakura !
Roger !
Nice, Mr. Garmillas.
I want to ask you, Führer Desler.
What brought you here ?
Who are you ?
My name is
My name is Ranhalt Desler.
Desler…
Desler ! Desler ! Desler ! Desler !
Fourteen years ago
How could this have happened ?
I, Abelt Desler, wasn't important
enough to keep Mother's soul in this world.
Why me ?
Uncle united all of Garmillas.
I'm entrusted to manage it,
and keep the terrible fact secret.
Once you lose hope, you'll also lose your soul.
If they find out that they have no future, Garmillas will…
This is the most certain way.
Ballerus Tower was built for that purpose.
We can't turn back.
In order for Garmillas to survive, we need Iscandar's…
Desler ! Desler ! Desler ! Desler !
My dear citizens of the Garmillas Empire.
In order to achieve everlasting peace in the universe,
further expansion and integration of Iscandarism is necessary !
It is God's will, as well as the
noble mission of every Garmillas citizen !
Bring as many planets as possible under the control of Garmillas as quickly as possible !
Turn your eyes beyond the
Magellanic Cloud for further expansion !
Rapid expansion brought Garmillas
unprecedented wealth and power…
…which birthed opposition to the Desler regime.
You became the target of assassination many times.
Even by family members, right ?
You're a dictator !
If you had died instead of Mathius…!
I fabricated the execution of my
brother's wife, and exiled her.
That was the best I could do for my brother.
You've grown.
Desler family…
Mother died in poverty.
Is it true that the planet Garmillas is about to die ?
Working in the outer galaxy, I can feel that we, the pure Garmillan, can't survive too far away from the planet Garmillas.
So, we must find a planet with the same environment,
or artificially create one and move the entire population…
…within half a century.
In order to bring such a tremendous plan into reality, you expanded your supremacy across space…
…while being condemned as a coldblooded dictator.
Alteration of the environment using meteorite bombs…
That's just…
Is it true that you're doing this to save Garmillas ?
So, what are you going to do ?
What difference does it make ?
Right now, I have no strength.
Whether I pray to the powerless
God or negotiate with Gatlantis…
…neither will give me an advantage.
Even so…
Even so, I…
What Teresa's power is needed most for is…
You should know.
It's the mother planet Garmillas.
That's why you've been…
W...wait, what are you talking about, Gamy ?
Ranhalt, the path is dreadful from here on.
If you're going to go with me, let go of emotion.
If you become emotional,
you'll make the same mistake I did.
Hey, don't listen to that bastard !
Keyman !
Sorry, Kodai.
Episode 15
Teresa, Cry For Desler !
Sotto oyasuminasai
A gentle goodnight
Kodai Susumu:
Shima Daisuke:
Sanada Shiro:
Nanbu Yasuo:
Aihara Yoshikazu:
Saijo Miki:
Kato Saburo:
Yamamoto Akira:
Saito Hajime:
Nagakura Shiori:
Hijikata Ryu:
Katsuragi Toko:
Ono Daisuke
Suzumura Kenichi
Otsuka Hochu
Akabane Kenji
Kokubun Masato
Moriya Satomi
Hosoya Yoshimasa
Tanaka Rie
Tochi Hiroki
Amagai Kazusa
Ishizuka Unsho
Kaida Yuko
Osanago no youna toiki
You breathe like a little child
Abelt Desler:
Klaus Keyman:
Gharder Talan:
Loren Barrel:
Lutz Karzet:
Adersia Desler:
Erich Desler:
Mathius Desler:
Teresa:
Elsa Desler:
Abelt Desler(child):
Gerd Aalen:
Garstein Frinza:
Zolf Dorgen:
Bargin Dorales:
Yamadera Koichi
Kamioya Hiroshi
Nakamura Kotaro
Terasoma Masaki
Onozuka Takashi
Ikeda Masako
Inoue Kazuhiko
Kusao Takeshi
Kanda Sayaka
Nokubi Naoko
Okada Emi
Kikumoto Taira
Harada Akira
Yano Masaaki
Fujinuma Kento
Itsumademo soba ni iru kara
I'll be by your side forever
Mabuta tojite
So close your eyes
Hidamari no takeru youna yasashisa de...
As gentle as warm sunlight...
...Tsusumi komu yo
...I'll embrace you
Shiawase umidasu chikara
The power to bring happiness
Fuwari fuwari fuwa fuwa yume no naka
Drifting and floating, feeling like I'm having a dream
Omoi haseru yorisoinagara
Cuddling up and thinking of you from afar
Itsudemo waratte ite hoshii to negau
My wish is for you to keep on smiling
Never let your childlike smile disappear
Ubu na egao tayasanu youni
Itooshii hito yo...
My dearest one...
Preview
I didn't know you were alive...
What's the meaning of this ?
If you want to kill me, do it later.
Fate appears to be completely linked together.
I'll rescue him, no matter what !
What was I trying to destroy at that time...?
Episode 16
Farewell, Teresa! Cast Bouquets for Two Deslers